# LÚCIA REIS

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER 

■ ROOMOLENSTRAAT 2A, AMSTERDAM, 1015AN, NETHERLANDS 

+31636334869

# ° DETAILS °

Roomolenstraat 2A, Amsterdam, 1015AN, Netherlands +31636334869 reis.lucia@gmail.com

> Place of birth Brazil

Nationality
Portuguese/Brazilian

° LINKS °

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u> Portfolio

# ° SKILLS °

Product Management
Experimentation
Product Improvement
Agile Methodologies
Creative Problem Solving
Front-end Development
Analytical Thinking
Cross-functional teams

#### LANGUAGES

Portuguese

English

Spanish; Castilian

Dutch; Flemish

German

#### ° HOBBIES °

yoga, watercolor, literature, traveling, cooking

#### PROFILE

Sr Product Manager experienced with various digital <u>products</u>, including content management systems, metadata and rights management, mobile gaming apps, video-on-demand, and e-learning platforms. I'm driven by curiosity and a dangerous taste for experimenting. Most of all, a gamer, a geek, a bookworm, a crime series addict, and an innovation enthusiast.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Senior Product Manager at SkyShowtime, Amsterdam

December 2022 — Present

- Led the product experience insights team, utilizing qualitative and quantitative data for continuous discovery to align business opportunities with customer needs.
- Defined UX research strategy for feature development validation and release impact, guaranteeing optimization of limited resources.
- Introduced agile practices and cross-functional continuous discovery, aligning business goals through a customer focus across the organization.
- Championed a shift from delivery to customer value mindset, enhancing prioritization and visibility of release impact through data-driven approaches.
- Eliminated 9% of empty search use cases, reducing the customer exit from service by 5% in Q1-24.

#### Product Manager at Liberty Global, Schiphol-Rijk

August 2019 — August 2022

- Led the content operation system roadmap for Video on Demand and Replay/Linear platforms across STB, web, mobile, and TV apps, encompassing metadata management, search, and recommendations APIs.
- Managed the end-to-end process from conceptualization to launch of a new architecture and CMS tool in 18 months, resulting in a 100% increase in team productivity.
- Oversaw the program management of technical integration and automation processes for content supply chain, including onboarding content suppliers in 8 countries within six months.
- Headed the Copywriting & Translations product and process, leading to a 15% reduction in Localization incidents.

#### Release Manager at Spil Games, Hilversum

July 2018 — June 2019

- Led development of web release management tool with automation and SEO/marketing version history, resulting in 20% reduction in release issues and faster in-app release process
- Provided guidance as product advisor for narrative game, collaborating with writers and game design team progressively improving conversion and retention.

# International Content Operations Manager at Bookchoice, London/Amsterdam

August 2016 — July 2018

- Led product strategy for content analytics enabling content acquisition teams to make data-driven decision on new licensing deals.
- Led redesign for web customer library, mobile e-book reader, and audiobook player reducing user friction and customer service tickets.
- Provided training and support to Content Operations team members.

# Head of Digital at Rocco, Rio de Janeiro

October 2012 — June 2016

# Digital Production Assistant at Zahar, Rio de Janeiro

July 2011 — September 2012

# EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration - MBA Digital Marketing & Design, Escola Superior de Propaganda e Marketing, Rio de Janeiro

2015 - 2016

Bachelor's degree Portuguese Language and Literature, Universidade Federal Fluminense, Niterói

2007 - 2012

# COURSES

Junior Developer, SheCodes.io

July 2024

Professional Scrum Product Owner I, Scrum.org

December 2020

Scrum & Agile, KnowledgeHut

January 2017

**Project Management PMBOK, FGV Online** 

January 2014

# **★** PROJECTS

# Colofão, Brazil

2014 — 2016

Digital Publishing Forum Founder and Columnist

# Revista Capitolina, Brazil

May 2015 — April 2016

Tech & Games columnist and Social Media Manager